

# MATTHEW CALLAHAN

Software Engineer | Phoenix, Arizona

#### **EDUCATION**



#### **University of Wisconsin-Madison**

Bachelor of Science, Geographic Information Systems

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Republic Services | Scottsdale, AZ | December 2018 - Present

Staff Engineer (May 2019 - Present)

- Lead a team of eight developers and testers, overseeing talent development, skill set improvement, and acting as a mentor to all team members.
- Established and implemented a standard application architecture for greenfield development, allowing developers to rapidly begin coding and reduce the time needed to deliver an MVP.
- Implemented unit test standards for the team and led effort to increase test coverage in all applications, reducing the number of production bugs.
- Authored coding conventions and style guide documents for developers and currently leading effort to refactor all applications to follow these guidelines.

#### Senior Developer (December 2018 – May 2019)

- Developed enterprise GIS web applications which provided customer data mapping and route visualization tools to assist in waste disposal operations.
- Developed APIs and services which provided data and analysis functions to other development teams and applications throughout the company.
- Supported desktop development for GIS data analysis and batch data processing.
- Implemented a Git branching strategy and code review process for all application repositories, increasing team throughput and code quality.

# Carvana | Tempe, AZ | February 2018 - December 2018

Software Engineer

- Primary job function was back end development to create and maintain the APIs and microservices which powered carvana.com using C#, .NET & .NET Core.
- Supported front end development to maintain and enhance a mobile responsive UI for vehicle inventory search engine (JavaScript ES6+, React & Redux).
- Implemented A/B testing to help drive data analytics and deliver the best UX.

#### CBRE | Tempe, AZ | March 2008 - February 2018

Application Developer (January 2011 – February 2018)

- Developed web applications which provided mapping, site selection, and data analysis tools for real estate brokers and their clients using ASP.NET MVC.
- Developed desktop applications for GIS data processing and analysis using C#, .NET, WinForms, MapBasic, ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, and Python.
- Administered on-prem servers (Windows Server, IIS, SQL Server, ArcGIS Server).

#### GIS Technician (March 2008 – January 2011)

- Developed scripts and desktop GIS tools to automate data analysis tasks.
- Created custom maps and market research reports for brokerage staff, affording them the ability to make well informed decisions and best serve their clients.

#### **ABOUT ME**

My name is Matthew Callahan, and I am a player-coach in the software world: I enjoy writing code and leading my team by example. I have over ten years of experience in web and desktop software development and continuing to learn the ever-changing landscape of programming is my passion.

#### CONTACT

Email: matthew.callahan@outlook.com

Phone: 630-988-1555

Homepage: mfcallahan.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mfcallahan1

GitHub: github.com/mfcallahan

**Blog:** seesharpdotnet.wordpress.com

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Microsoft Technology Associate: Developer

## **KEY SKILLS**

#### Languages

C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python

#### Frameworks

.NET & .NET Core, Angular, React, Node.js, ArcGIS

#### **Testing**

NUnit, Jasmine, Mocha, Selenium, Cypress

#### **Dev Tools**

Azure, Git, GitHub Actions, Jenkins, Splunk, SQL Server

Resume ver 2021.02.04